# Hanseul Cho (조한

Room 9410, Building No.9., 85 Heogi-ro, Dongdaemun-gu, Seoul, Republic of Korea

■ jhs4015@kaist.ac.kr | 😭 hanseuljo.github.io | 🖸 github.com/HanseulJo

in linkedin.com/in/hanseul-cho | • @hanseulio | © Google Scholar (Hanseul Cho)



# **Personal Profile**

I am a Master's candidate in the Optimization & Machine Learning (OptiML) Laboratory, advised by Prof. Chulhee Yun at Kim Jaechul Graduate School of AI (GSAI) in Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST). Before this, I received my Bachelor's degree in Mathematical Sciences (major) and Computing Sciences (minor) at KAIST in 2022.

My primary research interests lie in optimization, machine learning, and deep learning, mainly focusing on theoretical analysis of them. Recently, I have been looking at topics on various constrained and/or multi-level optimization problems, including minimax optimization (i.e., saddle point problem), fair machine learning, reinforcement learning, and more, with particular interest.

# Education

# Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Seoul, Republic of Korea

M.Sc. in Artificial Intelligence

Mar. 2022 - Jun. 2023(Expected)

· Advisor: Prof. Chulhee Yun (Optimization & Machine Learning (OptiML) Laboratoy, Kim Jaechul Graduate School of AI (GSAI), KAIST)

#### Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

B.Sc. in Mathematical Sciences

Mar. 2017 - Feb. 2022

- Minor in Computer Sciences
- Summa Cum Laude (GPA: 4.05/4.3)

#### **University of Twente**

Enschede, Netherlands

**Exchange Student Program** 

Feb 2020 - Jul 2020

• Major in Applied Mathematics

#### **Incheon Science High School**

Incheon, Republic of Korea

High School

Mar. 2015 - Feb. 2017

• Early Graduation (two-year course)

# Publication \_

#### INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCES/JOURNALS

• Cho, Hanseul and Chulhee Yun. SGDA with shuffling: faster convergence for nonconvex-PŁ minimax optimization. ICLR 2023. [OpenReview] [arXiv]

## **DOMESTIC CONFERENCES/JOURNALS**

- · Cho, Hanseul and Chulhee Yun. SGDA with shuffling: faster convergence for nonconvex-PŁ minimax optimization. Short version in 2022 Korea Al Association + NAVER Autumnal Joint Conference (JKAIA 2022).
  - NAVER Outstanding Theory Paper Award & Spotlight presentation.

#### **Preprint**

- · Lee, Hojoon\*, Hanseul Cho\*, Hyunseung Kim\*, Daehoon Gwak, Joonkee Kim, Jaegul Choo, Se-Young Yun, Chulhee Yun. Enhancing Generalization and Plasticity for Sample Efficient Reinforcement Learning. Under Review.
- · Lee, Junghyun\*, Hanseul Cho\*, Se-Young Yun, Chulhee Yun. Fair Streaming Principal Component Analysis: Statistical and Algorithmic Viewpoint. Under Review.

# **Experiences**

#### Machine/Deep Learning Theory + Physics (MDLTP) Seminar

Seoul, Republic of Korea

Jul. 2022 - Feb. 2023

- (Co-)Organizer • Homepage: sites.google.com/view/mdlt-p
- Jointly organized by OSI Lab, OptiML, and CSSPL
- Topics: Learning theory, loss landscape, trajectory analysis, (stochastic) optimization, high-dimensional statistics, statistical/mathematical physics, scientific machine learning, and more.

### **KAIST 2021 Post-AI Research Project**

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Undergraduate Researcher May 2021 – Dec. 2021

- Jointly advised by Prof. Sangyoon Yi (SOIL Lab, GSFS, KAIST) & Prof. Jinkyoo Park (Sys. Int. Lab, ISysE, KAIST)
- Project: Research on 'Al-augmented Organizations' of Collaborative Decision Making and Learning
- Contribution: (1) Devised a model-based randomized algorithm for single-player finite-horizon NK landscape optimization game; (2) Conducted some experiments on human-Al cooperation based on the algorithm that I devised

#### Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Mar. 2021 - Jun. 2021

Individual Study

- Advised by Prof. Jinwoo Shin (ALIN Lab, GSAI, KAIST)
- (1) gradient-based optimizers for large-batch setting (e.g., LARS & LAMB); (2) theoretical analysis on gradient clipping (paper reading)

### Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Individual Study

Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

Jun. 2020 - Aug. 2021

- Advised by Prof. Jong-chul Ye (BISPL, BBE, KAIST)
- Assignment: Semantic Segmentation of Kidney Tumor with U-Net (with KiTS19 Challenge Dataset)

### Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Individual Study

- · Advised by Prof. Yeonseung Chung (MAS, KAIST)
- Statistical learning theory

# Awards \_\_\_\_\_

2022	NAVER Outstanding Theory Paper Award, JKAIA 2022	Republic of Korea
2022	Summa Cum Laude, Bachelor's, KAIST	Republic of Korea
2017 - 2020	The National Scholarship for Science and Engineering, Korea Student Aid Foundation	Republic of Korea
2017 Fall	<b>Dean's List</b> , The School of Freshman, KAIST	Republic of Korea

# Skills

ProgrammingFamiliar: Python (PyTorch, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Jupyter, Pandas, etc.), MATLAB.Novice: C, C++, R, HTML/CSS, ScalarComputer Misc.Familiar: শ্রম্ (Overleaf/VSCode), Git, Microsoft Office.Novice: Adobe (Lightroom, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Photoshop)MusicPlaying the drums and percussions

# Languages

**English** Sufficient for academic activities: TOEIC score 925 (LC 460, RC 465) (2021.04.11)

**Korean** Native proficiency

**Others** Had some introductory courses on French, German, Classical Latin, & Chinese.